<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LTB | Jinning Wang</title>
    <link>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/tag/ltb/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/tag/ltb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>LTB</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/media/icon_hu34517862f4a1ff29f087ce92eb66ea20_25692_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>LTB</title>
      <link>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/tag/ltb/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best-of Open Source Libraries for Power System Analysis</title>
      <link>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/post/bestps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/post/bestps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jinningwang/best-of-ps&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;🏆 A ranked list of awesome open-source libraries and tools for Power Pystem Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a weekly updated ranking list of popular open-source libraries for power system analysis! Welcome to put your favorite packages on it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix Power Flow and TDS Initialization Error in ANDES</title>
      <link>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/post/andes_init_debug/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/post/andes_init_debug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As dsicussed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cuihantao/andes/discussions/386&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ANDES Discussions #386&lt;/a&gt;, the user may run into &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;power flow divergence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TDS initialization error&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; when revising cases file from given cases. In this blog, we will discuss how to fix these errors. The case files and source code can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jinningwang/jinningwang/tree/main/blogs/andes_init_debug&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;andes_init_debug&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;power-flow-divergence&#34;&gt;Power flow divergence&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AC power flow resutls are used as the initialization points of TDS. In ANDES, devices &lt;code&gt;Bus&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;PQ&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;PV&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Slack&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Shunt&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Line&lt;/code&gt; are used to solve AC power flow. Usually, the user may revise the system topology, such as adding new devices (&lt;code&gt;Bus&lt;/code&gt;) or changing load (&lt;code&gt;PQ&lt;/code&gt;). Belows are some possible reasons for failed power flow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power load unbalance is too large;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bus initial voltage and angle are inapproriate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;tds-initialization-error&#34;&gt;TDS initialization error&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After solving the AC power flow, the dynamic device can be initialized from the power flow results. Belows list some possible reasons for failed TDS initialization:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inapproriate limiter values, usually occurs in &lt;code&gt;TurbineGov&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Exciter&lt;/code&gt; if power flow is changed significantly;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inapproriate dynamic devcie parameters;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inapproriate equations in dynamic model, usually happens when developing new models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DiME and AGVIS A Distributed Messaging Environment and Geographical Visualizer for Large-scale Power System Simulation</title>
      <link>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/publication/agvis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/publication/agvis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This work introduces two open-source libraries of LTB for large-scale power system simulation, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CURENT/dime&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DiME&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CURENT/agvis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AGVis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distributed Messaging Environment (DiME) implements an asynchronous shared workspace to enable high-concurrent data exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Grid Visualizer (AGVis) is presented as a geovisualization tool that facilitates the visualization of real-time power system simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disturbance Propagation in Power Grids With High Converter Penetration</title>
      <link>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/publication/emw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/publication/emw/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Model Development Workflow in ADNES</title>
      <link>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/post/andes_dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/post/andes_dev/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on my personal development experience, I summarized this guide as a clue for those who want to try ANDES and develop models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-andes&#34;&gt;What is ANDES?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.andes.app/en/stable/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ANDES&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source Python library for power system modeling and simulation developed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://cui.eecps.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Hantao Cui&lt;/a&gt;. ANDES allows users to develop new models by their own will, which can be easily done by translating block diagrams into models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The philosophy of ANDES is introduced in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H. Cui, F. Li and K. Tomsovic, &amp;ldquo;Hybrid Symbolic-Numeric Framework for Power System Modeling and Analysis,&amp;rdquo; in  &lt;em&gt;IEEE Transactions on Power Systems&lt;/em&gt; , vol. 36, no. 2, pp. 1373-1384, March 2021, doi: 10.1109/TPWRS.2020.3017019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ANDES is currently under &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ACTIVE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; development and maintenance by Dr. Hantao Cui.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-develop-new-model-with-andes&#34;&gt;How to develop new model with ANDES?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two examples for development new models are available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.andes.app/en/stable/modeling/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Development&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before developing a new model, it is recommended to go through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.andes.app/en/stable/modelref.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Model reference&lt;/a&gt; and check out the existing groups and their functions. Then the following steps can be followed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you have installed ANDES in development mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check existing models that are similar to your model, and then draft the diagram of your model. Some standard model references are available on ESIG, Neplan, PowerWorld, and PSSE Model Library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When implementing the model, similar function pieces from existing models can help to reduce manual efforts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build your model and finalize it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-generate the pycode by &lt;code&gt;andes prep&lt;/code&gt;. Sometimes there occur multi-functionalities, where you may need &lt;code&gt;andes prep -f&lt;/code&gt; to re-generate all model codes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a test case file that includes your model, where the IEEE 14-bus system and Kundur system can be used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load the test case, and run the &lt;code&gt;ss.TDS.init()&lt;/code&gt; to see if the initialization is successful. If initialization runs into an error, you may need to tune the model initialization equations (&lt;code&gt;v_str&lt;/code&gt; defined in the model). Remember to run &lt;code&gt;andes prep&lt;/code&gt; and restart the kernel (for Jupyter Notebook users) every time you make a change to the model code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After finishing the model development, it is encouraged to check the code style (can be done by package flake8) and open a PR to contribute it into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cuihantao/andes&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ADNES repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-scale Testbed</title>
      <link>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/project/ltb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jinningwang.github.io/#about/project/ltb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The electric power grid is undergoing unprecedented modernization toward higher reliability, higher efficiency, and lower cost through the integration of renewable energy, wide-area monitoring, and advanced control technology. This integration is making the transmission grid overwhelmingly complex to understand and model to apply new control or actuation technologies. This calls for a fast-prototyping platform for research and testing under the new transmission technology paradigm. Such a platform should be highly integrated, closed loop, and capable of mimicking a real power grid for testing new controls or algorithms. However, traditional software simulation packages usually perform specific tasks such as dynamic simulation or state estimation but lack the capability of providing an integrated closed-loop platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
